<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="F5veRings.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="F5veRings.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-07-12T18:54:48+00:00</updated><id>F5veRings.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Martin Munguia&apos;s website. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">8 billion days left pt. 2</title><link href="F5veRings.github.io/blog/2024/8-billion-days-left-pt-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="8 billion days left pt. 2"/><published>2024-07-12T12:48:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-12T12:48:00+00:00</updated><id>F5veRings.github.io/blog/2024/8-billion-days-left-pt-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="F5veRings.github.io/blog/2024/8-billion-days-left-pt-2/"><![CDATA[<p>Last blog’s post got me a little bit riled up. Like, why wait until the Sun dies for me to write another blog post? I want to talk about another great leader and dear friend from ancient Mexico– His friends called him The Dog (In Latin, Chucho, legal name was Jesus) on account of him always going barefoot and other customs traditionally associated with canines.</p> <p>His running gag was that he would invite everyone over for barbecue and not actually make any food for other people– just a couple loaves of bread and fish for himself. And so if people Not In The Loop went up to him to complain about the food, he’d point at the latrine, just past the berry bushes and buckwheat and say in roman:</p> <p>-“Come caca!”</p> <p>Most actually did go into the latrine– such was their eagerness to be part of the party. (That’s where the term “shit-eating grin” comes from, actually). I, being a man of discernment, just picked a berry, ate it, and then said “no thanks, I’m full”.</p> <p>In his worldview, there were two kinds of people– Trash People, and Shit People. Trash goes in the trash bin, he’d say. Then in latin he’d add “Y las caquitas solitas se juntan” and go for a Christian hug (aka el abrazo del chucho, aka The Dog Lean). Great man. If only his breath wasn’t so bad… then again, he didn’t like kissing.</p> <p>And that’s a twofer today.</p> <p>-M</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Religion"/><category term="Spirituality"/><category term="Blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where I talk about the third most famous man in the Universe]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ONLY 8 BILLION DAYS LEFT</title><link href="F5veRings.github.io/blog/2024/only-8-billion-days-left/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ONLY 8 BILLION DAYS LEFT"/><published>2024-07-12T09:48:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-12T09:48:00+00:00</updated><id>F5veRings.github.io/blog/2024/only-8-billion-days-left</id><content type="html" xml:base="F5veRings.github.io/blog/2024/only-8-billion-days-left/"><![CDATA[<p>To Whom It May Concern:</p> <p>Look– Another arrow shooting up and away from the eastern front.</p> <p>I haven’t checked my notes, but I’d say there’s only eight billion arrows left, rounded up to the nearest billion for your comfort.</p> <p>I know what you’re thinking. You want to say “Martin, there’s no rush. I’m a learned man/woman/non-binary erudite. The Earth is round and there’s only the one Arrow, ever screaming overhead.”</p> <p>Or you might *also* be a heretic, and go as far as to say “that’s not an Arrow at all! It actually stays perfectly still, and it is Us that rotate/fly around it etc”.</p> <p>You’ve been lied to about all that. That Apollo’s Arrows are infinite or last forever– that’s a lie of comfort made to take each one of them for granted. In real life, do you ever look at an arrow headed your way and say “Egad! I wonder what’s for dinner!”?!</p> <p>No. If you’re lucky, you might have time to utter a quick blessing (“Dear, dear, dear, God…”). Usually, though, it’s a one word ejaculation– religious, scatological or sexual in nature. Our life’s preoccupations boiled down to four letters or less.</p> <p>Speaking of scatological , let me digress a minute here, since we’re all already dead anyway.</p> <p>Most of you might think I’m talking about the end times, saying I’m prone to wax eschatological. You’re sort of half right, thanks to serendipitous convergent etymology. My point is that at the end of everything, once anything is synthesized, assimilated, and digested, be it the Book of Apocalypsis, David Foster Wallace’s magnum opus Infinite Jest, or the Oopsie No Poopsie aromatic oil whose packaging you chortled over with your funcle at the Tukwila Mall, but especially Ideas (be it brilliant or dull), is all really the same thing once the shoe hits the floor: shit. That’s all the end times are– our life’s work revealed as a little pile that you just hope someone else will stumble upon and carry with, add to their own and even polish to a shine. Truth be told painfully, oftentimes their own hands are already full with other peoples’. Anyway. Back to my maint point– the death of today’s Arrow.</p> <p>Take a good look at the [Sun]. It’s Apollo’s gift to some poor old sod, maybe to no one and everyone in particular, maybe aimed right at Apollo’s own chest (if the round Earth theory is valid, anyway). Don’t shed a tear no matter what, lest the [Sun] in your eye drown.</p> <p>Let it burn inside your eye’s heart and carry on; perhaps in this way, that arrow can be salvaged, forever a little twinkling turd of what it once was. Just for today. Let it speak to you and guide your actions– it has a voice (everything does).</p> <p>Perhaps you’ll have the courage to quit that job that’s been holding you back on your happiness. Who needs that job when the Sun is literally dying overhead?</p> <p>Maybe it will give you the chutzpah–yiddish for terminal velocity– to escape the orbit of a failed relationship, or even better, to talk things out with that that person you love and resolve things in a way that makes you feel like you can die happy in a few hours alongside everyone else.</p> <p>In all likelyhood, though, they don’t love you back and they’re actually living their best life–saying “I Love You” is a lie of convenience akin to saying “the sun will never die” or “I’ll hit you up”. It’s what you tell someone in order for them to stop following you.</p> <p>That’s not your problem. Doth walk away scat-free– Thou spakest thine peace…</p> <p>That actually reminds me of Julius Caesar’s last joke. In honor of the end times– I’ll tell you how it went:</p> <p>So, Julius Caesar, contrary to all popular belief, was the emperor because he was the most ruthless Truth or Dare player. Anything you asked him to do, he’d do– that’s actually how he started going around naked: someone dared him to wear invisible clothes.</p> <p>He won literally everyone over with his fearless bravado, always doing the People’s will no matter the cost.</p> <p>But anyway, there’s this guy who wins an audience with him, a dingleberry flushed down the annals of history as Brutus– that’s latin for “It Could Be You”– who Truth or Dares him to, basically, kill himself. Julius Caesar loses his shit– he literally laughs so hard he would’ve pooped on his robes had he worn any that day!</p> <p>So he says to Brutus “Here’s a man fit to be a King!” He makes Brutus his second in command, makes him go everywhere with him, gives him proper clothes and everything, basically treats him like his best friend. Now, in Roman culture, this is a Bad Thing– Caesar invented the Roman Handshake for a reason–to pull people in a little Too Close. But Brutus knew nothing of royal customs– he was just a jokester, and foreshadowing is bad for jokes.</p> <p>So anyway, it’s the Caesars’ birthday, held at his summer mansion, and Brutus is the guest of honor. He arrives at sundown, duly on time. Everyone’s already passed out drunk and on the floor. Except Caesar, who lords over the dregs of the reverie from his penthouse balcony.</p> <p>As Brutus walks up the foyer, Caesar calls out to him in Latin: “Ah, Bruto! Hablando del rey de Roma!”</p> <p>He then, basically, slices his own throat and proceeds to take a quick trip down three floors headfirst.</p> <p>What’s really funny about it though, was that at the end of it all, Brutus lied to the centurions and stated that *he* killed Caesar over a dare just to be King for a day.</p> <p>Caesar still laughs about it and won’t let me live it down to this day.</p> <p>And that’s the Truth!</p> <p>-M</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Blog"/><category term="History"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Who killed Caesar? We all did!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EIGHT BILLION DAYS UNTIL THE SUN DIES</title><link href="F5veRings.github.io/blog/2024/eight-billion-days-until-the-sun-dies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EIGHT BILLION DAYS UNTIL THE SUN DIES"/><published>2024-07-11T11:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-11T11:55:00+00:00</updated><id>F5veRings.github.io/blog/2024/eight-billion-days-until-the-sun-dies</id><content type="html" xml:base="F5veRings.github.io/blog/2024/eight-billion-days-until-the-sun-dies/"><![CDATA[<p>To Whom It May Concern:</p> <p>It has recently come to my attention that we only have 8 billion days (rounded up to the nearest billion) until our dear Sun expires. Now, if this fact alone is making you quake with existential phantods, fret now; it’s only going to get worse. Picture this– Apollo is a giant giddy with booze, armed with only a handful of arrows (eight billion, rounded up to the nearest billion), shooting them up at the sky one by one. The directive might’ve been, a long time ago, to shoot us dead. But dear Apollo, perhaps, is taking a stand and today decided to look the other way. Either way, there will come a day where the quiver runs dry, or even worse– dear Apollo hits the mark and shoots us right in the heart. In honor of our impending demise, I have taken it upon myself to brew a (lightly roasted) pot of coffee, and chronicle each arrow in real time, from the moment it leaves its bow, to when it lands God knows where. The coffee is done brewing, but the arrow is still up in the sky. I would spill a little of my coffee in honor of the poor sod to catch it from Apollo today, but I am recently unemployed and coffee is very expensive.</p> <p>Cheers– we’ll all be dead soon,</p> <p>Martin</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Cute"/><category term="Doomsday"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A chronicle of utmost import]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Create a Personal Website and Blog for Free</title><link href="F5veRings.github.io/blog/2023/how-this-site-was-built/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Create a Personal Website and Blog for Free"/><published>2023-08-30T01:11:44+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-30T01:11:44+00:00</updated><id>F5veRings.github.io/blog/2023/how-this-site-was-built</id><content type="html" xml:base="F5veRings.github.io/blog/2023/how-this-site-was-built/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="creating-your-own-hosted-website-and-blog-for-free">Creating your own hosted website and blog, for free!</h2> <p>Hi all! I want to share with you how I built this blog. Most of the features in this site I borrowed from <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio">alshedivat/al-folio</a> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">al-folio</code>. In order to edit my posts I am currently using an open-source app called <a href="https://github.com/decaporg/decap-cms">Decap CMS</a>. In order to edit posts online, you need to validate against Github’s OAuth, but there’s no safe way to do that from a static site directly. Luckily, you can setup your own <a href="https://github.com/sveltia/sveltia-cms-auth">Decap CMS-compatible Cloudflare Worker</a> to run the authentication for you at no charge. I am currently running on Windows; if you want a Linux version of the tutorial, feel free to request it! This tutorial assumes you’re familiar with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">docker-compose</code>.</p> <h3 id="one-two-skip-a-few">One, Two, Skip a Few…</h3> <p>Well, why reinvent the wheel. The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">all-folio</code>’s <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/blob/master/README.md">README</a> is an excellent place to get started. This tutorial assumes that you are able to get the base site up and running in github-pages and that you have <a href="https://giscus.app/">gisqus</a> enabled.</p> <h3 id="almost-there-already">Almost there already!</h3> <p>So your site is up and running. Now we’ll add posts to it!</p> <h4 id="add-a-content-management-system-cms">Add a Content Management System (CMS)</h4> <p>We’ll be working with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">decaporg/decap-cms</code>. <a href="https://github.com/decaporg/decap-cms/blob/master/README.md">README</a> Setup is really easy if you’re on Netlify. We’re hosting it on Github Pages, so we’ll need to create our own OAuth server for it. I made my own and tested out several of the ones provided in their documentation to no avail, except for one that runs on Cloudflare Workers. The best part– it’s also free. Score.</p> <ol> <li>In the root folder, create an <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">admin</code> folder. We’ll add two files there: <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>admin
 ├ index.html
 └ config.yml
</code></pre></div> </div> </li> </ol> <p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">index.html</code></p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nn">---</span>
<span class="na">layout</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">default</span>
<span class="na">title</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Admin</span>
<span class="na">permalink</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">/admin/</span>
<span class="na">subtitle</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">login screen for decap</span>
<span class="na">title</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Login</span>
<span class="na">nav</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="kc">true</span>
<span class="na">nav_order</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="m">6</span>
<span class="na">dropdown</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="kc">false</span>
<span class="na">publish_mode</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">editorial_workflow</span>
<span class="na">media_folder</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s2">"</span><span class="s">assets/uploads"</span>
<span class="nn">---</span>
<span class="cp">&lt;!doctype html&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;html&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;head&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;meta</span> <span class="na">charset=</span><span class="s">"utf-8"</span> <span class="nt">/&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;meta</span> <span class="na">name=</span><span class="s">"viewport"</span> <span class="na">content=</span><span class="s">"width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0"</span> <span class="nt">/&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;meta</span> <span class="na">name=</span><span class="s">"robots"</span> <span class="na">content=</span><span class="s">"noindex"</span> <span class="nt">/&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;title&gt;</span>Content Manager<span class="nt">&lt;/title&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;/head&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;body&gt;</span>
  <span class="c">&lt;!-- Include the script that builds the page and powers Decap CMS --&gt;</span>
  <span class="nv">&lt;script src="https://unpkg.com/decap-cms@^3.0.0/dist/decap-cms.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;/body&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;/html&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">config.yml</code></p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>backend:
  name: github
  branch: master # Branch to update (optional; defaults to master)
  repo: your-repo/your-repo.github.io

publish_mode: editorial_workflow
media_folder: "assets/img/uploads"
public_folder: static/media

collections:
<span class="p">  -</span> name: "blog" # Used in routes, e.g., /admin/collections/blog
    label: "Blog" # Used in the UI
    folder: "_posts" # The path to the folder where the documents are stored
    create: true # Allow users to create new documents in this collection
    slug: "---" # Filename template, e.g., YYYY-MM-DD-title.md
    fields: # The fields for each document, usually in front matter
<span class="p">      -</span> {label: "Layout", name: "layout", widget: "hidden", default: "post"}
<span class="p">      -</span> {label: "Comments", name: "gisqus_comments", widget: "hidden", default: "true"}
<span class="p">      -</span> {label: "Title", name: "title", widget: "string"}
<span class="p">      -</span> {label: "Publish Date", name: "date", widget: "datetime"}
<span class="p">      -</span> {label: "Description", name: "description", widget: "string"}
<span class="p">      -</span> {label: "Body", name: "body", widget: "markdown"}
<span class="p">      -</span> {label: "Tags", name: "tags", widget: "markdown"}
<span class="p">      -</span> {label: "Categories", name: "categories", widget: "markdown"}
<span class="p">      -</span> {label: "related", name: "related_posts", widget: "hidden", default: "false"}
<span class="p">
  -</span> name: "news"
    label: "News"
    folder: "posts"
    create: true 
    fields:
<span class="p">    -</span> {label: "Layout", name: "layout", widget: "hidden", default: "post"}
<span class="p">    -</span> {label: "Comments", name: "gisqus_comments", widget: "hidden", default: "true"}
<span class="p">    -</span> {label: "Publish Date", name: "date", widget: "datetime"}
<span class="p">    -</span> {label: "Body", name: "body", widget: "markdown"}
<span class="p">    -</span> {label: "gisqus", name: "giscus_comments", widget: "hidden", default: "true"}
    inline: true
</code></pre></div></div> <p>This config file tells the CMS that we have two different collections of posts that we want to be able to create. It requires some kinds of fields, and others are conventions that <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">al-folio</code>’s posts already follow. You can add/edit to this list to some degree.</p> <p>Once you rebuild the website with docker-compose, you’ll notice you have a login button on your site. It won’t work out of the box because we’re not on Netlify due to OAuth requirements, so we’ll create one ourselves.</p> <h4 id="create-an-oauth-server">Create an OAuth “server”</h4> <p>Why go through all the trouble of creating an OAuth server just to login to a static site? Well, because you static sites can’t do server-side logic, which means they can’t exchange OAuth tokens with Github. For that, we need a tiny bit of server-side processing. So small, we could do without the server and run it off a Cloudflare worker.</p> <p><a href="https://github.com/sveltia/sveltia-cms-auth">Follow this tutorial</a></p> <p>You will need to create a Github OAuth App, a Cloudflare account, and enable Cloudflare Workers. Don’t worry, you can sign up for the free plan without payment info.</p> <p>Follow it to a T! Don’t be a smart guy like me and try to make sense out of Decap CMS’s documentation. It will lead you astray!</p> <h4 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4> <p>Hope you liked it. I will be editing this as I go. If I’m missing something feel free to request it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal-site"/><category term="jekyll"/><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to build a blog on Github Pages]]></summary></entry></feed>